<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="32"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Issue No. 2                                          CSUN College of                       JANUARY 2024
                                                             Engineering and
                                                             Computer Science














                SPR I N G  20 2 4


































           IGNITING THE CURIOSITY
           OF INNOVATORS




           Autodesk Technology Engagement Center
           Groundbreaking



           ASCE Pacific Southwest Symposium

           Held at CSUN


           Celebrating the Legacy

           of MEP]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[The Autodesk

                                                                             Technology
                                                                             Engagement

                                                                             Center construction
                                                                             is on its way, slated

                                                                             to be finished by
                                                                             early spring 2025.

                                                                             [page 6]]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[MESSAGE FROM THE DEAN






                                               Dear Friends,

                                                   e’re happy to have you back—both new and old—as we celebrate the long-
                                              Wawaited return of Spectra Magazine, the official publication of the CSUN
                                               College of Engineering and Computer Science.

                                               When we initially planned to relaunch the magazine, little did we know that a
                                               global pandemic would sweep across the globe, impacting us all. Throughout these
                                               challenging times, we have remained committed to providing our students with the
                                               exceptional education they deserve, while staying true to our educational mission.
                                               After a challenging two-year journey from our last issue, it’s time for us to emerge
                                               from our cocoon and bring you the latest stories, groundbreaking research, and
                                               remarkable achievements within the college once again.

                                               The college has undergone remarkable transformations since our last issue.
                                               Exciting projects like the Autodesk Technology Engagement Center are underway,
                                               carving a path for enhanced learning experiences for our students. New initiatives
                                               like the Matador Summer Transition to Engineering and Computer Science Program
                                               (M-STEP) are bridging college accessibility for incoming Freshmen, providing
                                               students with mathematical needs, the ability to boost their math skills before
                                               starting their degree program. Scholarship applicants within the College of
        HOUSSAM                                Engineering and Computer Science have achieved unprecedented levels of financial
                                               support this year, with more than 70 students receiving a total of over $300,000 of
                                               financial aid within the college. Furthermore, our master’s programs continue to
        TOUTANJI PH.D.
                                               expand, with the introduction of the Master of Science in Construction Management
                                               this Fall and a forthcoming Master's Degree in Data Science within the next year.
                                               And with all of this, a new generation of faculty and staff have joined us in the last
                                               year, bringing new methods of critical thinking into our college.

                                               We as engineers and computer scientists, remain steadfast in our resolve to drive
                                               advancements in STEM. While the past few years have been arduous for everyone,
                                               by exploring the endless possibilities of fields such as artificial intelligence,
                                               autonomous manufacturing, neural networks, and aerospace engineering, we
                                               aim to surpass the limits set by skeptics and prove that the impossible is indeed
                                               possible.
                                               Within the coming pages, we invite you to immerse yourself in this issue of Spectra
                                               Magazine. Learn about the latest developments, be inspired by captivating stories,
                                               and uncover tantalizing discoveries that will ignite your passion for engineering
                                               and computer science here at CSUN. We sincerely hope that you enjoy this edition,
                                               and we extend our warmest wishes to all of our readers.
                                               Sincerely,


                                               Houssam Toutanji, Ph.D., PE, F.ASCE
                                               Dean









     ON THE COVER:   View of the College of Engineering   SPECTRA  MAGAZINE is published by the College of   CONTRIBUTORS:
     and Computer Science at California State University,   Engineering and Computer Science at California State   Spencer Hutchison  •  Sarah Lifton
     Northridge in the San Fernando Valley.     University, Northridge for its alumni and friends.  PHOTOGRAPHY:
     On the following pages, a rendering of the new                                          Lee Choo  •  David Hawkins  •
     Autodesk Technology Engagement Center (ATEC),   18111 Nordhoff Street, Northridge CA 91330-8295  Spencer Hutchison
     with an inset photo of construction.       www.csun.edu/ecs                            GRAPHIC DESIGN:
                                                                                            Carolina Franco-Ardaghi SPECTRA
     4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[SPECTRA
        TABLE OF                        CONTENTS 2024

































                   06                             10                                 12                      16





   CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, NORTHRIDGE | COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING AND COMPUTER SCIENCE




                                                                04         MESSAGE FROM THE DEAN



                                                                06       ATEC GROUNDBREAKING
                                                                       Autodesk Technology Engagement Center


                                                                10       RESEARCH

                                                                         The Wonders of Gecko-Inspired Adhesives
                                                                       and Dr. Jamie Booth


                                                                12       NEWS
                                                                       The latest college news.

                                                                16     Celebrating the Legacy of MEP
                                                                       MEP Alumni Reunion event


                                                                28     GIVING

                                                                           Alumni giving back through scholarships.



        2024
                                                                                                                    5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[IGNITING THE CURIOSITY OF INNOVATORS








        AUTODESK



        TECHNOLOGY                                                                                          Andrew


                                                                                                            Anagnost ‘87,
                                                                                                            President and
        ENGAGEMENT                                                                                          Autodesk
                                                                                                            CEO of


        CENTER






        GROUNDBREAKING

        CEREMONY





            “MAKING IS A FRONT DOOR TO INSPIRING YOUNG PEOPLE TO DO MORE WITH
            TECHNOLOGY AND PURSUE A TECHNICAL EDUCATION,” SAID ANDREW ANAGNOST ’87
            (ENGINEERING), PRESIDENT AND CEO OF AUTODESK INC., THE SOFTWARE COMPANY
            WHOSE SUPPORT IS HONORED THROUGH THE FACILITY’S NAME. “BECAUSE WHEN
            THEY MAKE SOMETHING, THEIR CURIOSITY AND INTEREST ARE IGNITED. THAT’S WHAT

            THE AUTODESK TECHNOLOGY ENGAGEMENT CENTER IS ALL ABOUT: IGNITING THE
            CURIOSITY AND INTEREST OF THE NEXT GENERATION OF INNOVATORS.”



               n April 14, 2023, CSUN marked a significant moment with   and Justice Initiative, CSUN is the host campus for the new Global
               the ceremonial groundbreaking of the Autodesk Technology   HSI Equity Innovation Hub program, launching initiatives in the
               Engagement  Center,  officially  launching  a  center  of   region, statewide through the California State University system, and
        Oinnovation and exploration for students from preschool   nationally.
        through college. The facility will accommodate academic programs
        in the university’s College of Engineering and Computer Science,   The event brought together leaders from the state of California,
        equity-focused STEAM (science, technology, engineering, arts and   Autodesk  Inc.’s  leadership  including  CEO  Andrew  Anagnost,  and
        mathematics), and Global Hispanic Serving Institution (HSI) Equity   CSUN leadership such as President Erika D. Beck to emphasize the
        Innovation Hub programming.                            center's role in inspiring future innovators and creators. The occasion
                                                               showcased student projects, like a Formula SAE race car and an
        Autodesk Inc., a leader in design and make software, has provided   autonomous firefighting airplane, demonstrating the collaborative
        over $7 million in total support.  With Autodesk’s support, a feasibility   efforts between students and the institution. Additionally, Autodesk
        study set the course for the facility. A $25 million state allocation   presented a virtual reality experience to all attendees, to help highlight
        from California Gov. Gavin Newsom was made possible with support   the center's aim to ignite students' interest in technical education and
        from U.S. Sen. Alex Padilla, Congressman Tony Cárdenas and   its potential to offer opportunities for growth.
        Assemblywoman Luz Rivas — who all delivered heartfelt and inspiring
        remarks at the groundbreaking event. Padilla also helped secure $1   Set to open in early Spring 2025, the center will be located next
        million in federal funding.                            to Jacaranda Hall and it will house the latest cutting-edge labs for
                                                               research, design and digital capture spaces, a fabrication lab, and a
        With significant support from Apple Inc. as part of its Racial Equity   community maker space. (Excerpt from CSUN Today article).
                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[IGNITING THE CURIOSITY AND INTEREST OF


        THE NEXT GENERATION OF INNOVATORS.

































































        Top photo on left (from left): Dean Toutanji, President Beck, Andrew Anagnost, the Hon. Tony Cárdenas, Robert Taylor and the Hon. Luz Rivas. Photo by Spencer
        Hutchison. Top photo on right (from left): Andrew Anagnost (sitting in race car) with Dean Toutanji and members of the FSAE Car Project. Photo by Lee Choo.
        Bottom photo front row (from left): Michael Neubauer, president of CSUN's Faculty Senate; Amanda Quintero, senior advisor to the president for Inclusive Excellence
        and equity innovation officer for the Global HSI Equity Innovation Hub; Lillian Kimbell, CSU trustee; Wenda Fong, chair of CSU Board of Trustees; Jolene Koester, CSU
        interim chancellor and CSUN president emerita; Andrew Anagnost, president and CEO of Autodesk; Erika D. Beck, CSUN president; U.S. Senator Alex Padilla; Tony
        Cárdenas, Congressman for the 29th District; Luz Rivas, 43rd Assembly District; Houssam Toutanji, dean of CSUN's College of Engineering and Computer Science;
        and Shayan Moshtael, president of CSUN Associated Students. Second row: Colin Donahue, CSUN vice president for Administration and Finance and CFO; Steve
        Relyea, CSU executive vice chancellor for Business and Finance; Kim Grant, project executive of Hathaway Dinwiddie Construction; Elvyra San Juan, CSU assistant
        vice chancellor for Capital Planning, Design and Construction; Susan O’Connell, managing principal of AC Martin; Dara Treseder, chief marketing officer of Autodesk;
        Guillermo Melantoni, director of product management: Fusion 360 Education and Business Logic Integration and Autodesk Latinx Network ERG global lead; Robert D.
        Taylor, chair of CSUN Foundation Board of Directors; Jenish Bhavnagri, Associated Students senator for CSUN's College of Engineering and Computer Science; Nichole
        Ipach, CSUN’s vice president for University Relations and Advancement and president of the CSUN Foundation; Meera Komarraju, CSUN’s provost and vice president for
        Academic Affairs; William Watkins, CSUN's vice president for Student Affairs and dean of students; and Ranjit Philip, vice president for Information Technology and
        chief information officer. Photo by David J. Hawkins.
        2024
                                                                                                                    7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[NO ONE RISES ALONE:




       FROM CAL STATE




       TO THE C-SUITE






        By Andrew Anagnost '87, President and CEO, Autodesk*


            California is awash in contradictions. Its cultural, economic, and   my story. It didn’t end there
        geographic diversity makes it a compelling place to live, but it also has   because California has a
        huge gaps in education, opportunity, and wealth. And despite being   well-functioning safety net
        in the technology capital of the world, many of California’s residents   of educational institutions –
        don’t have access to the information, mentorship, and education   our community college and
        needed to thrive in today’s economy, one where the most lucrative   California State University
        jobs –enabling social mobility – will increasingly be in the tech sector.   systems catch the talent that
                                                               would otherwise not reach its
            We know that not every child in California grows up in a household   potential. After shaking off
        with tech-savvy siblings and college-educated parents with the time,   my bout of self-destruction,
        money, and inclination to hover over their education. If your family   I was caught by the California
        doesn’t know what’s changing in the world, you have little chance   State University at Northridge, where I studied engineering and was
        of preparing for it. We are in danger of having many of our most   mentored by incredibly caring and passionate educators. After two
        capable and motivated Californians slip through                        years  there,  I  had  the  grades  to  transfer  to  a
        the cracks of opportunity, further exacerbating                        UC, but stayed at CSUN because I had found a
        economic and social divides. It doesn’t have   "TODAY, I RUN ONE OF    community  invested in both my sense of self
        to be this way. I know, I was one of those who                         and education. After graduating, I worked as
        slipped through the cracks.              THE MOST IMPORTANT            an engineer for Lockheed in Burbank, and went
                                               SOFTWARE COMPANIES IN           on to get a master’s and PhD from Stanford.
            I came of age in the San Fernando Valley                           Today, I run one of the most important software
        of the late 70’s and early 80’s. My father, the   THE WORLD. BUT IT WAS   companies in the world. But it was in the
        child of Greek immigrants, and my mother, the   IN THE CALIFORNIA STATE   California State University system that I learned
        daughter of a Quaker and a Spanish construction                        first-hand that not all those with potential can
        worker. My father was a social worker and later   UNIVERSITY SYSTEM THAT   follow a straight line to achieve it, and no one
        an administrator for the California Department   I LEARNED FIRST-HAND   rises alone.
        of Rehabilitation, and my mother attended night
        school to become a nurse practitioner. I was a   THAT NOT ALL THOSE        Now I’m part of a company that believes
        latchkey kid raised by well-intentioned parents   WITH POTENTIAL CAN   everyone should have access to the tools
        who were often simply trying to survive.   FOLLOW A STRAIGHT LINE      and education required to succeed in a world
                                                                               increasingly driven by technology. At Autodesk
            I read adult fiction and college-level   TO ACHIEVE IT, AND NO     we make software for people who make things
        biographies in elementary school, was obsessed                         – from buildings and roads, to cars and robots,
        with space exploration, and learned in a way   ONE RISES ALONE."       to  games  and  movies.  All  our  software  is  free
                                 poorly suited                                 to  students.  Of course,  we  have a  commercial
                                 for traditional classrooms. My   interest: we have customers, employees, and shareholders to satisfy.
                                 parents didn’t know what to do with   But we also believe in the positive potential of what we do. And for me,
                                 me, my teachers tried their best,   it’s personal.
                                 and my friends increasingly came
                                 from the margins of society. None   When I returned to my alma mater five years ago, I saw a powerful
                                 had the  information or  capacity   gateway institution, one that had grown to become one of the largest
                                 to guide me. By the time I was in   Hispanic Serving Institutions (HSIs) in the country. CSUN now reaches
                                  high school, I was deep into drug   a whole new demographic of immigrant and first-generation students.
                                   abuse, bad behavior, and self-  Many of them, as my father and mother were, will be the first in their
                                    destruction. I was accelerating   families to get a college degree. But CSUN needed more investment in
                                    my own fall through the cracks,   technology and engineering to help these students succeed. Thanks
                                     leading to arrests, a brief stay   to the efforts of the University’s President Erika Beck, elected officials,
                                     in juvenile hall, probation, and   and the generosity of several companies, I return to the place that
                                     a crushingly low sense of self-  quite literally saved me, to see the groundbreaking of the Autodesk
                                     worth.                    Technology Engagement Center. I’m proud of the students who will be
                                                               California’s next generation of innovators. And I look forward to helping
                                      But  that’s not  the  end of   keep more of them from falling through the cracks.
        Andrew Anagnost, CSUN Industry                         *Published with permission from the author.  First published April 2023.
        Association Meeting, 1986.
                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[*Published with permission from the author.  First published April 2023.
        2024                                                   Rendering of the Autodesk Technology Engagement Center (ATEC) Courtyard area.
                                                                                                                    9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[RESEARCH










             THE WONDERS


             OF GECKO-



             INSPIRED


             ADHESIVES


             AND


             DR. JAMIE BOOTH




                      By Spencer Hutchison



              When we see a gecko effortlessly climbing walls or ceilings,   technologies. The gecko’s unique ability to switch between
              it appears almost magical. But this extraordinary ability is   strong attachment and easy detachment could revolutionize
              rooted in the gecko’s toe-pads, which feature an intricate   these fields.
              structure of hair-like fibers. Thanks to a prestigious $300,000
              grant from the National Science Foundation (NSF), Dr. Booth   Translating the principles governing gecko adhesion into
              and his team of dedicated students are delving deep into   practical engineering solutions poses a significant challenge.
              the science behind this phenomenon, exploring how we can   Dr. Booth emphasizes that the foundation of these solutions
              reproduce gecko-inspired adhesives, with the potential to   lies in biology—a testament to the captivating interplay
              revolutionize various fields.                                        between the natural world and
                                                                                   engineering that still has many
              This grant, awarded through                                          unknowns.
              the Mechanics of Materials and   “I BELIEVE IT IS ESSENTIAL
              Structures (MOMS) program,      TO APPROACH TEACHING                 Dr. Booth’s research is far from
              is dedicated to advancing                                            a solitary endeavor. He actively
              fundamental research          WITH ENTHUSIASM BECAUSE                involves both graduate and
              in mechanics, materials,          WHEN YOU SHOW UP                   undergraduate students from
              and structures. Dr. Booth’s                                          CSUN in his laboratory and classes.
              specific research focus lies    WITH PASSION, IT OFTEN               The students play a vital role
              in exploring the “Origins of      RESONATES WITH THE                 in experimenting, building and
              Statistical Variation in Strength                                    understanding the impact of surface
              in Micropatterned Adhesive     STUDENTS. YOU GET BACK                roughness and the mechanics of
              Contacts”, or simply investigating   WHAT YOU PUT IN.”               defect formation.
              why there are differences in
              how well tiny patterns stick to   DR. BOOTH EMPHASIZES.              “I believe it is essential to approach
              surfaces and figuring out what                                       teaching with enthusiasm because
              causes these differences.                                            when you show up with passion, it
                                                                 often resonates with the students. You get back what you put
              And within the college, Dr. Booth’s Bioinspired Mechanics   in.” Dr. Booth emphasizes. “For instance, in the NSF project
              Lab is well-suited to do this investigation. By studying   we’re currently working on, we have incorporated a course-
              these gecko adhesives and the fibers of geckos, it’ll offer   based element. The goal is to introduce a project where
              numerous potential applications, from climbing robots and   students can contribute real and meaningful data, moving
              industrial automation to biomedical devices and wearable   away from merely a superficial exercise.”



                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[THE NSF GRANT ENCOMPASSES A THREE-YEAR
              DURATION, DURING WHICH THE TEAM HOPES TO
              ACCOMPLISH THEIR PREDEFINED GOALS.




              The process of developing and testing these gecko-inspired   patch. This comprehensive approach spans a wide range of
              adhesives is a complex journey. In their laboratory, students   scales, addressing the complexities of the defects and finding
              are actively engaged in every step of the process alongside   possible adhesive solutions from there.
              Dr. Booth. They begin by fabricating the adhesives using
              a meticulous molding process. The molds themselves are   When asked about why this project in particular, he had this
              designed by students and then extensively produced in their   to say: “I’m a fracture mechanics person. I am fascinated by
              machine shop. These same students are also responsible for   the study of fracture in engineering materials. There are so
              the molding process, carefully crafting accurate adhesive   many interesting techniques used in nature to prevent cracks
              samples for testing.                             from growing through structures. People most likely don’t
                                                               think of geckos as preventing cracks from causing fracture
              To gauge the adhesive’s load-bearing capacity, Dr. Booth’s   when they see them climbing walls, and that is part of what
              team has devised a solid experimental platform. As   makes it such a fun application of mechanical engineering.”
              the adhesive is brought into contact with a surface and
              subsequently retracted, the forces involved are carefully   The NSF grant encompasses a three-year duration, during
              measured. Visualizing the interface and gaining insights   which the team hopes to accomplish their predefined
              into how defects propagate or individual fibers detach are   goals. However, the research itself possesses the potential
              pivotal to their research. To facilitate this, the students have   for continued exploration. Dr. Booth explains that as long
              engineered a specialized setup for contact visualization,   as intriguing avenues and unanswered questions await
              delivering high-resolution images of the contact and non-  exploration, the research can extend its horizons. The
              contact regions using precise illumination techniques.  duration of the research journey will ultimately hinge on
                                                               the discoveries made and the subsequent directions their
              After exploring this contact visualization through practical   investigations take.
              work, students then migrate to the numerical side of their
              research. Various types of simulations are employed to   As the grant-funded research progresses, Dr. Booth and his
              model different processes occurring across varying length   team are well on their way to shedding light on the secrets of
              scales. These simulations offer insights into the formation   gecko adhesion and revolutionizing the future of adhesives
              of defects over rough surfaces, the                      and materials science. This endeavor exemplifies
              mechanical performance of individual                     how inspiration from the natural world yields
              structures, and even the behavior of an                  innovative solutions for our modern problems.
              array of structures within an adhesive























           Dr. Jamie Booth and
           students working in
           the Adhesives Lab.










        2024
                                                                                                                    11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[SPECTRA NEWS
       NEWS






              PSWS - PACIFIC SOUTHWEST

              SYMPOSIUM AT CSUN




            From Thursday March 23rd to Saturday March 25th 2023,
            California State University, Northridge (CSUN) was abuzz with
            energy as the annual Pacific Southwest Symposium (PSWS) took
            place on its campus. With a rich history as one of the largest and
            most rewarding events for engineering students in the region, the
            American Society of Civil Engineers' PSWS brought together over   CSUN students at the steel bridge competition.
            1,500 students and 14 universities spanning Arizona, California,
            Nevada, and Hawaii to partake in various competitions, both local
            and nationwide. This three-day extravaganza was much more
            than a competition; it was a celebration of engineering brilliance
            and comradeship involved with Civil Engineering.

























            First day of symposium, display of concrete canoes and steel bridges.

            CSUN students made their mark at PSWS, securing an 8th place   diverse range of events that challenged their engineering prowess.
            overall out of 14 universities. Their prowess was evident in a   From the society-wide competitions of ASCE Concrete Canoe
            couple of competitions: receiving 2nd place in the Steel Bridge   Competition to the Timber Strong Design-Build Competition, to
            Competition overall, and 3rd place in the Timber Strong Design-  the local technical competitions of the Geowall Competition to the
            Build competition. CSUN's excellence extended to the local   DeCADthalon Competition, PSWS left no aspect of civil engineering
            DeCADthalon competition, where they emerged as champions.  unexplored.

            In the Steel Bridge Competition, CSUN achieved an impressive   The first day of PSWS centered around project showcases, where
            2nd place in construction speed, completing their bridge in just   students demonstrated, in board presentations and judging, to
            15 minutes and 2 seconds. Their bridge also secured the top   showcase the materials and processes behind their respective
            position in lightness, with a remarkable weight of 248.6 lbs and   projects. Alongside this, students from all the schools proudly
            an impressive stiffness rating of 0.69 Agg D(in).  displayed their concrete canoe and steel bridge projects in front of
                                                               the University Library, engaging with curious onlookers and sharing
            Despite a pre-construction score of 186 (already high compared   insights into how they got their projects to the final stage, along
            to other schools), CSUN dominated the Timber Strong Design-  with answering questions they may have. Throughout this, students
            Build competition with the highest construction points, an   from various schools were participating in a survey competition,
            impressive 118 out of 130.                         recording measurements and getting judged based off accuracy
                                                               and overall results of their work done.
            Over these three action-packed days, students participated in a

                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Following this, the second day is when the big competitions began.   complete with awards, speeches by Dean Toutanji and Mario Mazed
        Heading out to Hansen Dam, the concrete canoe competition was in   of CSUN's College of Engineering and Computer Science, and lively
        full spring, where students were having their boats rigorously tested   dancing and relaxing as the sun set on this eventful symposium.
        for buoyancy, strength, and speed through slaloms and sprints.
        While students competed for top honors and the fastest times on   The Pacific Southwest Symposium not just showcased these
        the pre-determined course, activities like tug-of-war and volleyball   students’ technical skills but also their ability to connect,
        added an element of enjoyment to the proceedings.      collaborate, and make a positive impact on the field of civil
                                                               engineering. PSWS continues to be a beacon of excellence, inspiring
        Finally, Saturday was dedicated to the Steel Bridge competition



                               Geowall competition.








                                                                                                         Concrete canoe
                                                                                                         competition.






























                                                                             Center, CECS Dean and civil engineering and construction
                                                                             management faculty and students on the last day of
                                                                             competition. Above, students from the CSUN team proudly
                                                                             displaying their awards at the symposium banquet. Photos
          Timber Strong Design-Build                                         by Spencer Hutchison and Carolina Franco-Ardaghi.
          competition.



        and the Timber Strong Design-Build competition. Steel bridges   the engineers of tomorrow to reach new heights. A special thank you
        were evaluated based on construction speed, lightness, stiffness,   goes to Mario Mazed and the student planning team within CSUN's
        and aesthetics. Timber buildings were tested based off structural   College of Engineering and Computer Science for their tireless efforts
        integrity, design, speed of assembly, and weight-bearing   in organizing the event. And a thank you to the continued support of
        capabilities. While this was occurring in the parking lots on CSUN’s   ASCE and various company sponsors for ensuring the event's success,
        campus, the DeCADthalon unfolded in Jacaranda Hall's Civil   reflecting a shared commitment to building up the next generation of
        Engineering Lab (JD 1565), showcasing students' problem-solving   engineers.
        skills. The day culminated in a grand celebration at Blomgren Ranch,


        2024
                                                                                                                    13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[2
                                                                  1





              SENIOR DESIGN


              PROJECT


              SHOWCASE                                                                                                5


              The Senior Design Project Showcase is an annual full day event that
              showcases senior design projects that engineering and computer
              science students have worked on the year prior to graduation.
              Senior design is a major part of a student’s education as it puts in
              practice what they have learned and demonstrates the mastery
              of their disciplines and their problem-solving skills.  Often these
              projects go on to compete in both national and international
              competitions.
              The Senior Design Project Showcase features oral presentations
              as well as project exhibitions that are evaluated by high profile                                     9
              industry professionals to determine the winning projects.  We
              hope to see you at the 2024 showcase event which is scheduled for
              Friday, May 3rd at the Extended University Commons.

































                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[2                                                       3                                                            4















                                           6                                          7                               8



                                         1. Real Time Traffic Monitoring project, Computer Science Department, presentation to judges.
                                         2. Cleanbot 3000, Electrical and Computer Engineering Department.
                                         3. Jacob Wright, Formula SAE Car Project student member, presenting to Dean Toutanji; Kenneth Luna, Chair
                                         of the Linguistics Department; Amanda Quintero, Senior Advisor to the President for Inclusive Excellence and
                                         Equity Innovation Officer for the Global HSI Equity Innovation Hub; and Meera Komarraju, Provost and Vice
                                 10      President for Academic Affairs
                                         4. Smart Morphing Wing, Mechanical Engineering Department, presentation to judges.
                                         5. Steel Bridge, Civil Engineering and Construction Management Department, presentation to judges.
                                         6. Alpha Vision / 200 Vermont, Civil Engineering and Construction Management Department
                                         7. Autonomous UAV,  Electrical and Computer Engineering Department
                                         8. Human Powered Vehicle, Mechanical  Engineering Department.
                                         9. Grand Prize Winners, the Pure Shredder team, Manufacturing Systems Engineering Department, with
                                         Associate Dean Xudong Jia (left) and Faculty Advisor Gus Elias and MSEM Department Chair John Pan (right)
                                         10. Oral presentation,Simply Algorithms project, Computer Science Department
                                         Below, students, judges, faculty advisors and others came together for a group photo at Showcase. Photos by
                                         Spencer Hutchison.
































        2024
                                                                                                                    15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[CELEBRATING





       THE LEGACY





       OF MEP                                                    center. Over the 23 years that MEP was in existence, this structure

                                                                     students in common sections of their classes, and a study
                                                               helped transform the college experience for thousands of students,
                                                               demystifying the academic environment, teaching them how to
         By Sarah Lifton                                       use it to their advantage and providing meaningful incentives for
                                                               success. It proved so effective that other colleges and universities
                                                               soon began establishing MEP programs based on his concept.
            When Raymond B. Landis, a young CSUN engineering faculty
        member, rolled out the Minority Engineering Program, or MEP, in   Potential participants were identified through teacher/counselor
        1973, he based the concept on his own undergraduate experience, as   referrals, community organizations, and student search services
        well as the experience he had had mentoring minority students a few   and were then invited to apply to CSUN and MEP. The inaugural MEP
        years earlier.                                         group at CSUN consisted of 20 freshmen, two of whom went on to
                                                               earn their degrees five years later. The following fall, 30 new students
            “…[W]orking with these students had a profound effect on me,”   entered; 55 entered in 1975; 66 in 1976; and, in subsequent years,
        he later wrote. “It showed me that there were students who had the   75 new freshmen joined the program annually.
        capability to succeed in engineering study but would fail—primarily
        because there was a mismatch between what they needed and   MEP remained an active, successful program at CSUN and
        what their educational environment provided. I decided then that   elsewhere until the passage of Proposition 209, after which it was
        when I finished my PhD, I would attempt to build an educational   phased out. But in creating a pathway for success in engineering
        environment within a predominantly white engineering school that   and computer science for students who have traditionally had had
        would work for minority students.”                     neither exposure to nor opportunity to enter STEM fields, it helped
                                                               bridge education and achievement gaps to ensure the success of
            The innovative model Landis developed was grounded in   traditionally underserved students.
        two objectives: building a strong peer group and providing strong
        support from role models. MEP (later renamed MESA Engineering   The enduring impact of MEP prompted a very special event on
        Program) consisted of an orientation course, a system for clustering   September 10, 2022. Forty-nine years after the program’s inception,
                                                               alumni from the first graduating class to the last held a reunion
                                                               picnic on campus, in the Jacaranda Hall breezeway. Some 95 alumni
                                                               attended, including Pilar Montes (’78, ’84 Computer Science),






























                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Above, a view of the day's event in photos.  At the center from right, President
         Beck, Robert Taylor '82, Omoné O. Livingston '96, and Dean Toutanji.
         Below on opposite page, MEP reunion attendees, alumni, faculty, and students.
                                                                                 “If you want to go fast go alone.
                                                                                If you want to go far go together.”
         one of the first two MEP graduates. In addition, three former MEP             African Proverb
         tutors attended, as well as Gigi McGuire (’84 ’08), now CSUN Assistant
         Director, Partnerships & Initiatives; former MEP faculty directors Steven   "Early in the process it was clear that CSUN was
         Stepanek (CS), Behzad Bavarian (MSEM), Nagi El Naga (ECE), and Robert
         Ryan (ME and former associate dean). CSUN President Ericka Beck was   the right place for me to attend college. CSUN
         there, along with CECS dean Houssan Toutanji and Robert D. Taylor   had the attributes that I was seeking in my
         (’82), board chair of the CSUN Foundation and an MEP alumnus. The   college experience, beginning with high-quality
         event was planned by a committee made up of Taylor, who served as   classroom instruction by full professors, but also
         committee chair; McGuire; Omoné O. Livingston (’96); Armando Tellez   industry exposure, leadership opportunities, and an
         (’15); Lupita D. Montoya (’89); and Karina G. Zambrano (’99).
                                                                       unpretentious vibe. And, it was affordable, which was
            The alumni pledged over $20,000 to endow the MEP Alumni    crucial for a kid with big dreams and little money.
         Scholarship, which will provide scholarships to students active in the
         National Society of Black Engineers (NSBE), the Society of Hispanic   The Minority Engineering Program (MEP) made
         Professional Engineers (SHPE) and the Society of Women Engineers   CSUN the perfect place for me. In MEP I found a
         (SWE).                                                        community and a mentor. They did what community
                                                                       and mentors do — they had my back, but they
            Lupita Montoya (’89 Applied Mechanics), summed up the reason
         for the high degree of alumni commitment. “MEP brought together   kept me grounded. The impact on me of these
         minority students who aspired to become engineers,” she said.   extracurricular highlights was and remains profound.
         “However, for some of us, it also helped us develop a social
         conscience that mapped our long-term professional careers.    MEP awakened me to the most formative citizenship
         Some of us have stayed on that uncharted path and still       and leadership lesson that I have learned to date.
         work together to promote engineering among marginalized       The right answer is the goal of the student and
         communities. It is wonderful to find other MEP alumni who have   important to being a citizen or leader. However,
         done the same in their own spheres.”
                                                                       something more is required to be good at either.
            The college hopes to establish a chapter of the MEP Alumni   My experience as part of the MEP community and
         Association to continue strengthening the bonds between the campus   a mentor’s coaching taught me the power that can
         and those who benefited from the program.                     be unleashed by helping others succeed and the
                                                                       satisfaction that comes from doing so. It was in the
                                                                       crucible of MEP that my orientation began evolving
                                                                       from simply showing and telling others the right
                                                                       answer to helping and supporting them to succeed
                                                                       and win.

                                                                       Over the years since graduating, I’ve encountered
                                                                       circumstances that dictated that I go alone.  But
                                                                       I always recognized that I journeyed as a scout
                                                                       extending the trail of those who came before me.
                                                                       The trail is cleared by performance but paved by
                                                                       creating opportunities for others and helping them
                                                                       succeed.  I think this is an insight and ethic shared
                                                                       by many who benefited from MEP.  And this is MEP’s
                                                                       central legacy."

                                                                       Robert D. Taylor '82 Engineering, MEP Alumnus
                                                                       CSUN Foundation Chair
        2024
                                                                                                                    17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[M-STEP: A KICKSTART
        CONTINUING THE MEP

        TRADITION                                      TO SUCCESS IN

        MEP laid the groundwork for later              ENGINEERING AND
        programs dedicated to bridging
        equity gaps in engineering,                    COMPUTER SCIENCE
        computer science and other
        STEM-related fields. At CSUN,
        that momentum is evident in
        President Erika Beck’s vision of a                As graduating high school seniors prepared to start their first year
        brighter and more equitable future             of college this fall at California State University, Northridge (CSUN), some
        for everyone. One example of                   incoming freshmen had a head start on their coursework through CSUN’s
        that commitment is the Matador                 Matador Summer Transition to Engineering and Computer Science Program
        Summer Transition to Engineering               (M-STEP).
        and Computer Science Program                      Created by CSUN’s Student Success and Equity Programs Coordinator
        (M-STEP), which debuted last                   Vanessa Hernandez, Dr. Vinicius Sauer, Dean Houssam Toutanji, and Associate
        summer. A three-week summer                    Dean Xudong Jia of the College of Engineering and Computer Science (CECS),
        bridge program, it helps incoming              M-STEP is a free 3-week summer bridge program designed to help prepare
        first-time freshmen in the College             first-year students majoring in engineering or computer science fields. The
        of Engineering and Computer                    program focuses on boosting students’ math skills to get them ready for
        Science boost their math skills                the rigorous calculus and general mathematics courses they will take their
        to meet the requirements of                    freshman year.
        their major; facilitates students’                Beyond academics, M-STEP also helps students transition to college life.
        transition from high school to                 Through workshops and special events, participants learn essential skills like
        college coursework; and enables                time management, goal setting, and study strategies. They also get to connect
        them to meet CECS faculty, staff,              with CECS student clubs and alumni to gain motivation and insights about
        and students. As in MEP, these                 potential careers.
                                                          At the core of the 3-week program is the AI-powered ALEKS online
        students were made a part of                   learning platform. ALEKS assesses each student’s current math knowledge
        a cohort, registering them for                 then creates a customized program to teach them the concepts they need for
        the same courses, and helping                  calculus and beyond.
        to create a greater sense of                      ALEKS facilitates a continuous mastery of concepts by assessing
        community. The pilot resulted                  individual student knowledge gaps and understanding at the start of each
        in a 25% improvement in math                   course. Utilizing this information, it tailors a dynamic path for students
        ability, allowing students to start            to learn and master topics at their own pace. This personalized approach
        the academic year in higher-level,             empowers students to achieve proficiency in their course material, fostering
        required math courses and giving               ongoing learning and growth.
        them a head start on graduation.                  Participants work in ALEKS for the majority of each day, practicing math
                                                       problems and taking daily quizzes to track their progress. The goal is to fill any
                                                       knowledge gaps and get students ready to dive right into credit-bearing math
                                                       classes in the fall.


                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     18]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[M-STEP goes beyond math preparation to foster a sense of
                                                               belonging for new students at CSUN. Through college-hosted
                                                               workshops and special events, participants engage with current CECS
                                                               students, gaining valuable insights into the vibrant community and
                                                               experiences awaiting them within CECS.
                                                                  One in particular was the “Meet the Clubs” event, which
                                                               introduced M-STEP participants to 9 student organizations they
                                                               could join during their time here at CSUN. From the Society of
                                                               Women Engineers to the FSAE Matador Motorsports team, there was
                                                               a student organization for all interests.
                                                                  Aside from these events, students also attended workshops
                                                               on essential skills needed for college. For example, a workshop on
                                                               time management, where they built up skills necessary to ensure
                                                               timeliness of submitted work and how to keep their academic
                                                               journey manageable.
                                                                  With an inaugural cohort of 44 students completing the
                                                               program and participating in the award ceremony this July, M-STEP
                                                               is already demonstrating success. Some participants from the
                                                               program have scored high enough on their ALEKS final assessment
                                                               to place out of usually required pre-calculus classes. And the overall
                                                               GPA of students who participated in the program is 3.05 as of
                                                               January 2nd 2024, resulting in a B average.
                                                                  The College of Engineering and Computer Science hopes to
                                                               continue refining and expanding the program. Possible ideas include
                                                               extending the program length to 4 - 6 weeks, opening eligibility to
                                                               more incoming students, and conducting additional outreach so
                                                               students can plan further in advance for the summer opportunity.
           Above, students participating in the Meet the Clubs event. Below,
           student working on coursework through ALEKS. On opposite page, first   If its first year is any indication, M-STEP is poised to become a
           co-hort of M-STEP students at the culmination of the 3-week  summer   pipeline for many future Matador engineers and computer scientists.
           program. Photos by Spencer Hutchison.               By giving students a head start on college-level academics and
                                                               connections, the program aims to improve retention and reduce time
                                                               to graduation for future generations of students to come.




          NEW STUDENT

          WELCOME EVENT






              Hosted annually in early Fall, the New Student Welcome
           event generally takes place on the North University Library
           Lawn and in the Jacaranda Hall Breezeway. Tailored for
           first-semester Freshmen, Transfer, and Graduate students,
           this occasion serves as a warm introduction to the College
           of Engineering and Computer Science, guiding them in
           establishing connections with peers, faculty, staff, and the
           broader campus community.
              The event is designed to encourage interaction among
           new students, offering both games and enjoyable activities
           for them to participate in, along with some light refreshments.   Above, students enjoying the New Student Welcome Event.
           Motivational speakers also share their experiences and
           provide insights on how students can thrive within the college.
              This year, the event garnered an impressive attendance.
           Particularly noteworthy was the participation of students   students, discussing his excitement for these new students to
           from the inaugural Matador Summer Transition to Engineering   be at CSUN and offering insights on maximizing their academic
           and Computer Science Program, who engaged in sharing their   experience. The students left the event with a sense of engineering
           recent experiences of embarking on their journey at CSUN and   and computer science pride and were given a clear mission: to get
           within the college.                                 started on their programs, work hard, and achieve great things in
              In addition, Dean Houssam Toutanji addressed the   their future.


        2024
                                                                                                                    19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[INSPIRATIONS
       INSPIRATIONS







             MEGAN NGO'S PATH TO THE

             WOLFSON SCHOLAR AWARD




              By Spencer Hutchison
                 In 2022, CSUN celebrated the outstanding achievements
              of its graduating class at the annual Honors Convocation.
              Megan Ngo, a graduate in Computer Science from the College
              of Engineering and Computer Science, was honored with the
              prestigious 2022 Wolfson Scholar Award during this event.
              Megan's journey serves as a clear example of how the support
              from college programs like Attract, Inspire, Mentor, and Support
                         2
              Students (AIMS ) played a vital role in her success. And with
              her receipt of the Wolfson Scholar award, it shows that with
              unwavering determination, one can overcome any obstacle.
                 The Wolfson Scholar award, named after CSUN's inaugural
              vice president, Leo Wolfson, is a distinguished accolade
              reserved for outstanding students who have demonstrated
              exceptional academic performance and made notable
              contributions to both CSUN and the broader community.      Megan holding her CECS Distinguished Graduating Scholar Award,
              This prestigious recognition is bestowed upon individuals   an additional award she received on graduation day, 2022.
              who consistently exhibit excellence, both inside and outside   career pathways. AIMS  in particular is dedicated to furnishing
                                                                                 2
              the classroom. To be considered for this esteemed award,   resources and opportunities to students from Hispanic or low-income
              candidates must have made substantial contributions that   backgrounds with a passion for engineering or computer science
              positively influence CSUN and/or the wider community.  garnering national recognition from Excelencia, UEDA (University
                 Megan not only met but exceeded the award’s criteria.   Economic Development Association) and the White House Initiative
              With a remarkable 3.98 grade                                         for Educational Excellence for Hispanics.
              point average and active                                                Megan's involvement in the AIMS
                                                                                                               2
              participation in renowned       MEGAN ADVISES FUTURE                 program extended beyond receiving
              programs like the College of                                         assistance. Initially relying on her mentor
              Engineering and Computer        CSUN STUDENTS TO GIVE                for guidance in adapting to college life,
              Science’s AIMS  program, she      THEIR BEST, AND THAT               she eventually assumed the role of mentor
                         2
              unequivocally proved herself as                                      herself, guiding freshmen and transfer
              the rightful recipient of the 2022   EVEN IN THE FACE OF             students in navigating campus resources
              Wolfson Scholar title.           CHALLENGES, COLLEGE                 and selecting suitable courses. In doing so,
                 In selecting the College                                          she not only extended a helping hand to
              of Engineering and Computer    MARKS A NEW BEGINNING                 others, but also forged enduring friendships,
              Science at CSUN, Megan                FOR EVERYONE.                  establishing lifelong connections with the
              recognized the opportunities                                         students she aided.
              it offered individuals with                                             Now, armed with her bachelor's
              disabilities. Additionally, it                                       degree and the Wolfson Scholar Award,
              provided her the platform to delve deeper into her passion for   Megan is poised to continue her contributions to the development
              programming, an interest that had ignited during her high   of assistive technology applications through her pursuit of an
              school experience with an AP class.               MBA at CSUN. As a graduate student, she plays a pivotal role in
                 However, Megan's journey to receiving the Wolfson Scholar   a groundbreaking initiative known as A11Y+, a project dedicated
              Award was not without its challenges. As a first-generation   to promoting inclusivity and best practices for teaching inclusion
              college student, she initially felt unprepared for the academic   and accessibility, particularly in Hispanic Serving Institutions. Her
              transition from high school, grappling with the pervasive   ultimate aspiration through this endeavor is to champion the cause
              imposter syndrome that often plagues engineers and computer   of assistive technology, endeavoring to create greater opportunities
              scientists worldwide.                             for those in need.
                 Yet thanks to programs like AIMS  funded through the   In a closing reflection, she underscores the importance of
                                          2
              U.S. Department of Education, Megan not only received   not burdening oneself with excessive pressure. Megan advises
              the support she needed to embark on her higher education   future CSUN students to give their best, and that even in the face
              journey, but also gained invaluable experience and resources.   of challenges, college marks a new beginning for everyone. And as
              These resources included professional mentors, workshops,   Megan's story illustrates from this starting point, truly remarkable
              paid internships for undergraduate research, and prospective   work can emerge from humble beginnings.
                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     20]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[FROM DUAL DOCTORATES TO A YOUNG

             SCIENTIST AWARD: DR. CARPITELLA’S JOURNEY


             THROUGH ENGINEERING AND MATHEMATICS


              By Spencer Hutchison


















                                                                                                   Dr. Silvia Carpitella
                                                                                                   teaching a class
                                                                                                   about Manufacturing
                                                                                                   Management.
                                                                                                   Photo by Spencer
                                                                                                   Hutchison.
                 In the realm of academia, certain individuals stand out   engineering, working on a research project at her alma mater.
             not only for their groundbreaking research but also for the   Which during that time, a subsequent adventure to Spain led her
             accolades that recognize their exceptional contributions. Dr.   to the possibility of a double doctorate program, igniting her love
             Silvia Carpitella, a professor within the College of Engineering   for the country and prompting her to pursue a second doctoral
             and Computer Science at CSUN, is one such individual. Having   degree in mathematics, accomplishing both doctoral degrees
             received the Otto Wichterle Award, a Young Scientist Award   in 2019. From there, she’s continued to explore the world, gain
             from the Czech Academy of Science, along with achieving two   industry experience, and build connections.
             doctoral degrees at a young age, Dr. Carpitella is leading the   Dr. Carpitella's current research focuses on critical areas
             way in educational prowess.                       like supply chain management, production and operations
                 The Young Scientist Award, an annual distinction bestowed   management, and their integration with teaching methodologies.
             upon 25 scientists under 35, stands as a testament to her   A significant aspect of her work involves delving into the
             exceptional achievements. Notably, this award not only   digital transformation of practices in industrial maintenance
             celebrated her accomplishments in her field of research but   management, a subject that holds vast potential for innovation.
             also provided additional funding for her forthcoming research   She is equally passionate about evaluating the role of human
             endeavors, underscoring her dedication to pushing the   resources in an era of increasing automation. Dr. Carpitella
             boundaries of knowledge.                          believes in developing systems that empower individuals based
                 In addition to this honor, her outstanding contributions   on their unique skills, melding motivation with cutting-edge
             also garnered her doctoral thesis prizes from both The   technologies.
             Polytechnic University of Valencia and the Fondazione   Furthermore, she is dedicated to bridging the gap between
             Ingl. Luigi De Januario for their recognition of excellence in   theoretical methodologies and practical implementation, ensuring
             mathematical sciences and in the realm of industrial plant   that research findings are not confined to the realm of theory but
             management, respectively.                         are applicable and beneficial in real-world industrial settings.
                 Moreover, these awards have fortified her standing within   Collaborating with students on research is a key element
             the academic community, enabling stronger collaborations   of her vision. Dr. Carpitella believes this hands-on approach not
             with fellow faculty members and opening doors to potential   only enhances student learning but also contributes significantly
             research partnerships with other institutions and industries. Dr.   to their development. Her aspiration is to be a supportive and
             Carpitella's achievements have reverberated through the vibrant   influential figure in the lives of her students, unlocking their full
             research environment at the college, inspiring students and   potential and creating an environment that encourages students
             faculty alike.                                    to explore their passions and delve into various research topics,
                 Considering her educational journey, it becomes evident   fostering a community of driven learners.
             why Dr. Carpitella is such a valued addition to the college. After   As Dr. Carpitella's journey continues, it is clear that her
             completing her bachelor's and master's degrees in management  dedication to teaching, research, and her continued achievements
             engineering at Universita degli studi di Palermo, she embarked   will leave a mark on the College. She is a testament to the power
             on her first doctoral degree on innovation and technology   of hard work, perseverance, and the impact that one dedicated
                                                               individual can have on an academic community.
        2024
                                                                                                                    21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[SPECTRA NEWS

            DR. SHAWN SUN'S COMMITMENT TO

            STUDENT GROWTH



             By Spencer Hutchison

















                                                                                          Dr. Shawn Sun
                                                                                          (below) and graduate
                                                                                          students (above)
                                                                                          working on a project.
                                                                                          Photos by Spencer
                                                                                          Hutchison.


                                                                 After a stint in industry, Dr. Sun aspired to impart practical wisdom
                                                                 in academia, to help shape and mold the generations of students to
                                                                 come. He then started working at Louisiana Tech University as an
                                                                 assistant professor. During this time, Dr. Sun led a significant study
                                                                 sponsored by the Louisiana Transportation Research Center, titled
                                                                 "Load Rating of Existing Continuous Stringers on Louisiana’s Bridges."
                                                                 With the collaboration of two other professors and the participation
                                                                 of students, this research had profound implications empowering
                                                                 bridge owners to make informed decisions and significantly save in
                                                                 costs.

                                                                 With all of his educational and practical experience, he came to
                                                                 CSUN to help not only shape future engineers, but also to investigate
                                                                 some truly exciting projects. In 2023 alone, Dr. Sun provided research
                                                                 assistant positions to 12 undergraduate and graduate students,
            Dr. Shawn Sun, an assistant professor of Civil Engineering and   significantly contributing to their academic and professional
            Construction Management in the College of Engineering and   development while advancing his research projects.
            Computer Science, has made significant contributions to civil   These research interests revolve around improving civil infrastructure
            infrastructure and education. His impactful work has garnered   performance and exploring new materials and structural systems.
            more than a dozen accolades, including the NASA MUREP MPLAN   He actively incorporates emerging technologies, such as 3D printing
            Award, Precast/Prestressed Concrete Institute (PCI) Daniel P. Jenny   of various types of concrete, to advance construction practices
            Fellowship, Easton Foundation Faculty Fellowship in Engineering,   and enhance structural performance within these projects, giving
            and The Engineers' Council Outstanding Engineering Achievement   students the latest and greatest advancements.
            Merit Award, for his exceptional research activities and continued
            contribution to the field of structural engineering.  Recently, Dr. Sun is serving as the Principal Investigator (PI) on
                                                                 a PCI-funded research project, collaborated closely with industry
            As an educator and researcher specializing in structural engineering,   partners to identify critical parameters for the stability analysis
            Dr. Sun actively cultivates students’ potential through research   of precast girder transport vehicles. This initiative marked the first
            opportunities and hands-on experience inside and outside the   nationwide collection of rotational stiffness data for these vehicles,
            classroom with his own groundbreaking work. "I believe in the   offering students invaluable hands-on experience as they worked
            cascading effect of the engineers I send off into the world," he   alongside Dr. Sun in this significant field.
            proclaims. "They have the potential to create something wonderful."
            Dr. Sun's commitment to merging practical knowledge with academic   But by tirelessly merging research, collaboration, and mentoring,
            teaching has been a cornerstone of his career. His academic journey   Dr. Sun is making a profound impact— with the core of his work
            began with a B.S. and M.S. in China, culminating in a Ph.D. under the   sparking inspiration for our students to enhance civil infrastructure
            mentorship of Professor Maher K. Tadros, an internationally renowned   and build our communities for the better. As he continues to work
            expert in prestressed concrete, at the University of Nebraska-Lincoln   hard and strive for better education for his students, Dr. Sun is on the
            (UNL).                                               right path to stoke these young engineers to help shape a brighter
                                                                 engineered world.
                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[NEW GRANT FOR UNDERSERVED

               STUDENTS IN STEM AND MORE




              California State University, Northridge has been awarded a   mentoring,” Ramesh continued. “To put it simply, our students
              five-year, $3 million Title V grant from the U.S. Department   cannot succeed to the best of their abilities unless we give the
              of Education DHSI (Developing Hispanic Serving Institutions)   faculty the tools they need to help our students succeed.
              program for the creation of a new project to increase the number
              of underrepresented students studying science, technology,   “We anticipate that the project will positively impact
              engineering, mathematics (STEM) and the arts, and health sciences   approximately 6,000 students at CSUN and our partner
              and to close equity gaps.                        community colleges over the five-year duration of the grant at
                                                                      an average cost of less than $500 per student,” he
              “Strengthening Equitable Culturally Responsive          said.
              Environments (SECURE) for Student Success (SfS ),”
                                               2
              a collaborative effort between CSUN, Los Angeles        Ramesh said SfS  will be “all encompassing” when it
                                                                                 2
              Pierce College in Woodland Hills and College of the     comes to students. The project includes support for
              Canyons in Santa Clarita.               SECURE for      community college students before and after they
                                                    Student Success   transfer to CSUN; summer workshops; internships,
              “Our goals are quite simple, but impactful,”            industry engagement and career advisement;
              said CSUN electrical and computer engineering           research opportunities with stipends; faculty and
                                       2
              professor S.K. Ramesh, director of SfS . “We hope to increase   industry mentors; peer mentors; and undergraduate research
              enrollment, improve academic performance — including retention   symposiums, as well as ways to involve family members.
              and graduation rates — and reduce equity gaps. To that end, the
                                                                 2
              project will expand and enhance curriculum, research fellowships   SfS  is closely aligned and complements CSUN’s Road Ahead
              and culturally-responsive, work-based learning experiences in in-  Strategic plan under the able leadership of President Beck
              demand industry sectors for our students.        and colleagues campuswide.  “If we want our students to
                                                               truly succeed, then we take and explore different approaches
              “For the project to be successful, and this is key, we are providing   to education — different approaches to how we teach and a
              support and increasing faculty capacity to plan and implement   deeper appreciation for how our students learn.” [Excerpt from
              culturally-responsive pedagogies, proactive advisement and   CSUN Today article 1/24/24]



               OPPORTUNITIES ABOUND WITH

               HONORS CO-OP




              Sometimes the most meaningful learning takes place beyond the   must relate to their career goals and meet the college’s academic
              classroom and laboratory.                        standards.
              That’s the rationale behind the Honors Co-op, a longstanding   “Not surprisingly, Honors Co-op helps students jumpstart their
              CECS program offering a unique professional opportunity to top   careers,” said Vidya Nandikolla, associate professor of mechanical
              seniors. Honors Co-op places honors students in paid internships   engineering and current Honors Co-op Academic director. “More
              with industry partners for a year while they concurrently complete   than three quarters of Honors Co-op students ultimately accept
              the coursework for their bachelor’s and master’s degrees. It not   permanent positions with their industry sponsors.”
              only gives them real-world experience applying the knowledge
              and skills they’ve gained in college, but the students also tend to   Honors Co-op is a team effort. Employers work closely with the
              develop better interpersonal and communication skills than non-  Honors Co-op director, faculty evaluators and, of course, the
              participants; they learn how to budget time and money and be   student, developing a strong relationship with the college in the
              part of a professional project team; and they usually improve their   process. Placement with industry partners rewards students with
              grade point averages.                            meaningful work that enriches their understanding of their chosen
                                                               technical specialty and the corporate environment. Sponsors pay
              The Honors Co-op was established in 1986 after industry   the student a reasonable wage and provide allowable company
              representatives reached out to the college seeking technical   benefits. The program also allows an employer to train potentially
              apprentices. Applicants, who are carefully screened, must have   permanent employees and to compete favorably for top graduates.
              a minimum 3.0 overall GPA and must have completed all lower-
              division engineering or computer science courses. Once they   It’s no exaggeration to say that Honor Co-op is a win for the
              are selected, the students work half-time during the academic   industry partner, a win for the student, and a win for the college.
              year and full-time during the summer; they also earn six units of
              elective credit. The projects they are assigned by the employer   For more information about Honors Co-op, email ecshonorsco-op@
                                                               csun.edu.

        2024
                                                                                                                    23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[WELCOME NEW FACULTY
        Since our last issue, CSUN’s College of Engineering and Computer Science has hired several outstanding
        faculty who bring a wide variety of talents and expertise to the university.

        2023









        Marjan Asadinia            Myung (Michael) Cho        Rashida Hasan               Mohamed Hegab
        Computer Science           Electrical & Computer Engineering   Computer Science   New Chair of Civil Engineering and
        Assistant Professor        Assistant Professor        Assistant Professor         Construction Management
        Prior to joining CSUN, Marjan   Myung (Michael) Cho's research   Rashida Hasan's research interests   A tenured professor at CSUN since
        Asadinia served as an Assistant   interests encompass signal   include machine learning, data   2004, Mohamed Hegab was elected
        Professor at Cal Poly Humboldt   processing, optimization, and   mining, and deep learning. Her   Chair of Civil Engineering and
        University and Bradley University.   machine learning. His work revolves   current research projects include   Construction Management, succeeding
        With a background in computer   around leveraging structural   data preprocessing: Feature   Nazaret Dermendjian who served as
        architecture and memory    information in data representation   Selection, Feature Extraction, and   chair since 2010 and has now joined
                                                                                          the faculty early retirement program.
        technologies, Her research has   and network topology to enhance   Outlier/Anomaly Detection for static   Dr. Hegab has prior experience in
        focused on efficient algorithms for   recovery performance and reduce   and streaming data.  She actively   building and directing the Construction
        processor allocation, application   complexity. His areas of research   contributes to several peer-reviewed   Management program at CSUN. He
        mapping, and task migration in   are signal processing with structural   conferences and also serves as a   has served as an ABET evaluator since
        Network-on-Chips (NoCs) and   information, machine learning   reviewer. Apart from research, she   2005, reviewing programs worldwide for
        System-on-Chips (SoCs), as well   algorithms for processing Big   loves music, poetry, and astronomy.   accreditation purposes. He specializes
        as emerging Non-Volatile Memory   Data in a distributed manner,   She received her B.S. in Computer   in project controls and claims analysis,
        (NVM) technologies. She holds a   and optimization with structural   Science from the University of Dhaka,   and holds numerous professional
        Ph.D. in Computer Engineering from   information. He holds a B.Sc. from   Bangladesh. She holds an M.S. and   licenses. He earned his B.S. and M. S.
        Sharif University of Technology.  Hanyang University and a Ph.D.   Ph.D. from the University of Louisiana   from Cairo University and a Ph.D. from
                                   from the University of Iowa, both in   at Lafayette, both in Computer   North Dakota State University.
                                   Electrical and Computer Engineering.  Science.

        2022









        Sepideh Abolghasem          Qais Amarkhil              Vartenie Aramali           Silvia Carpitella
        Manufacturing Systems Engineering   Civil Engineering & Construction   Civil Engineering & Construction   Manufacturing Systems Engineering
        & Management Associate Professor  Management Assistant Professor  Management Assistant Professor  & Management Assistant Professor
        With prior experience at the   Qais Amarkhil worked in the   Vartenie Aramali has focused on   Silvia Carpitella's research interests
        University of los Andes, Sepideh   construction industry before   earned value management systems   include bridge engineering and
        Abolghasem aims to improve   transitioning to academia at his   for integrated project and program   math, focusing on decision support
        understanding of process parameter   alma mater. He is a Fulbright and   management, particularly for the   systems, uncertainty treatment in
        relationships and material   Rotary International Scholar, holds a   U.S. Dept. of Energy. Her broader   human evaluations, mathematical
        microstructures. Her research has   B.S. in Civil Engineering from Kabul   interests include front-end planning,   modeling, and optimization of safety
        integrated Operations Research   Polytechnic University (KPU), along   EPC contracts, project delivery   and supply chain management
        and Materials Science into this   with having completed his M.S. and   approaches for power plant projects,   in industrial settings. She has
        work, focusing on machining   Ph.D. in Construction Management   and construction safety. She actively   teaching and research experience
        manufacturing processes, and   Technology at Purdue University   contributes to peer-reviewed   in the US, Czech Republic, Brazil,
        recently, she has explored machine   West Lafayette. His research focuses   journals and serves as a reviewer   Spain, England, Germany, and
        learning techniques combined with   on project and organizational   for ASCE's Journal of Construction   Italy. She is actively involved in
        simulation for predicting material   performance, improvement of   Engineering and Management   co-supervising doctoral theses and
        properties. Additionally, she has   project planning techniques, and   and Journal of Management in   lecturing international scientific
        been actively involved as the faculty   construction operation modeling   Engineering. She holds a B.S. in   internships. She has a B.S. and M.S.
        advisor at IISE and represented                        Mechanical Engineering from Notre   in Management Engineering from
        Latin America on INFORMS’   and simulation. He integrates   Dame University-Louaize, an M.S.   Università degli Studi di Palermo, and
        International Activities Committee.   construction management practices   in Engineering Management from   a Ph.D. in Technological Innovation
        She holds a B.S. in Industrial   with advanced technologies to   the American University of Beirut,   Engineering from the University of
        Engineering from Sharif University   enhance productivity, sustainability,   and a Ph.D. in Civil, Environmental,   Palermo, and a Ph.D. in Mathematics
        of Technology, and M.S. and Ph.D.   and workplace safety in construction,   and Sustainable Engineering from   from Universidad Politécnica de
        degrees in Industrial Engineering   with numerous articles published in   Arizona State University.  Valencia.
        from the University of Pittsburgh.  peer-reviewed journals.
                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     24]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[SPECTRA NEWS

         2022









        Alex Modarresi              Rasoul Narimani            Melih Papila               Tohid Sardarmehni
        Computer Science            Electrical and Computer    Mechanical Engineering     Mechanical Engineering
        Assistant Professor         Engineering Assistant Professor  Assistant Professor  Assistant Professor
        Alex Modarresi brings a diverse   Rasoul Narimani's research   Melih Papila brings over 25   Tohid Sardarmehni's primary
        educational background and   concentrates on developing   years of academic and industrial   areas of expertise include machine
        expertise in computer networking.   optimization and control algorithms   experiences with broad expertise   learning, optimization, prediction,
        His research concentrates on   to enhance the efficiency of electric   in advanced composites. Holding   and control, with a particular
        network resilience, software-  power systems. He joined us from   a Ph.D. in Aerospace Engineering   focus on developing and testing
        defined networking, and the   Arkansas State University, where   from the University of Florida,   algorithms for autonomous driving,
                                    he received the Faculty Excellence
        Internet of Things. Recently, he   Award Emerging Scholar in 2021.   he was a recipient of Marie Curie   intelligent control systems, and
        has focused more on studying   He conducted postdoctoral work   International Outgoing Fellowship   stability/convergence analysis. For
        resilience in environmental   in Electrical Engineering at   which funded his collaborative   the past eight years, he has been
        science, such as smart agriculture   Texas A&M University, focusing   research at Stanford University.   dedicated to utilizing reinforcement
        systems. He also has extensive   on Cyber Physical Power   Prior to CSUN, he served as a faculty   learning to solve complex control
        experience in simulation including   Systems. He was honored with   member in the Materials Science   problems, with a primary goal of
        network protocols and system   the Grainger Power Engineering   and Nano-Engineering Program   finding optimal control solutions.
        dynamic simulation in agricultural   Award for his contributions.   at Sabancı University.  During his   He earned his B.S. from Shahid
        systems. His qualifications also   He has a B.S. in Electrical and   tenure he supervised 6 Ph.D., 17   Bahonar University of Kerman in
        include various certifications from   Electronics Engineering from Razi   M.S. and numerous undergraduate   Mechanical Engineering, an M.S. in
        Cisco Systems. He holds a M.S. in   University, an M.S. in Electrical   students. His current research   Mechanical Engineering from the
        Computer Science from Ryerson   Engineering from Shiraz University   focuses on energy efficient   University of Tabriz, and a Ph.D.
        University, along with a Ph.D.   of Technology, and a Ph.D. in   manufacturing and bondable/  in Mechanical Engineering from
        in Computer Science from the   Electrical Engineering from   de-bondable assembly strategies   Southern Methodist University.
        University of Kansas.       Missouri University of Science and   for architected structural designs
                                    Technology.                made of sustainable and multi-scale
                                                               advanced composite materials.

         2021









        Sahabul Alam               Maya Pishvar                Natalie Schaal             Chuanbing (Shawn) Sun
        Electrical and Computer Engineering   Mechanical Engineering   Mechanical Engineering   Civil Engineering and Construction
        Assistant Professor        Assistant Professor         Assistant Professor        Management Assistant Professor
        Previously a Postdoctoral Fellow at   Maya Pishvar’s expertise lies   With a diverse research background   Shawn Sun brings over 19 years
        Carleton University, Sahabul Alam's   in materials science, focusing   covering solid mechanics,   of expertise in research, teaching,
        research interests include aerial   on mechanics, processing, and   earthquake nucleation, and   and professional practice in
        communications, machine learning-  characterization of fiber-reinforced   educational interventions,   structural engineering. His research
        assisted wireless design, smart   composites. Maya is skilled in   Natalie Schaal is actively   focuses on areas such as ultra-high
        grid communications, and non-  assessing materials behavior,   engaged in projects exploring   performance concrete, innovative
                                                               dynamic strength characteristics
        orthogonal multiple access (NOMA).   conducting mechanical testing,   of aluminum and supporting   structural systems, sustainable
        He has contributed over 30 technical   and utilizing analytical techniques.   mentored research for minoritized   construction, structural stability,
        papers to journals and conferences   Additionally, she has proficiency   students. Committed to diversity,   additive manufacturing of concrete,
        in his field and serves as a reviewer   in numerical simulation, CFD,   equity, and inclusion, she actively   and autonomous construction.
        for various IEEE transactions and   FORTRAN, MATLAB, and SolidWorks,   contributes to student success   He has served as a principal
        conferences. Dr. Sahabul Alam   and has co-authored over 15 articles   activities, serving as one of two   investigator on over ten research
        holds a B.S. in Electrical and   in reputable scientific journals   Student Equity Faculty Advocates   grants and holds a patent for a wind
        Electronic Engineering from Khulna   and conference proceedings. She   in the Office of Student Success at   tower system. He has played key
        University of Engineering and   obtained a M.S. in Mechanical   CSUN since Fall 2022, along with   roles as a lead project engineer or
        Technology, along with a M.S. in   Engineering from Amirkabir   holding various leadership roles   project manager in eight significant
        Telecommunications Engineering   University of Technology and a Ph.D.   in student-focused initiatives.   projects that received national
        and a Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering   from the University of Oklahoma.  She obtained a B.S. in Mechanical   design awards. He holds a Ph.D.
        from the University of Quebec. He                      Engineering from the University   in Structural Engineering from
        was awarded the Governor General of                    of Portland, along with a M.S. and   University of Nebraska-Lincoln.
        Canada Gold Medal during his Ph.D.                     Ph.D. in Mechanical Engineering
        for academic excellence.                               from the California Institute of
                                                               Technology.
        2024
                                                                                                                    25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[SPECTRA NEWS

            2021
                                              RECENT GRANTS

                                              •Behzad Bavarian (Manufacturing Systems Engineering and Management) has received
                                               $18,375 from the Savannah River National Laboratory, in support of a project, “Tank Bottom
                                               Corrosion Control Monitoring for Materials Technology & Energy Section.”
                                              •Nhut Ho, Amiel Hartman (Mechanical Engineering), Xunfei Jiang (Computer Science)
            Abishek Verma                      and Kacie Blackman (Health Sciences) have received $77,596 from the Administration
            Computer Science Assistant         for Community Living, in support of a project entitled “Development of Semi-Autonomous
            Professor                          Wheelchair and Socially-Aware Robot Health Aid to Encourage Community Participation for
            Abhishek Verma's research          Persons with Low Mobility.”
            interests span Data Science, Big   •Bradley Jackson (Electrical and Computer Engineering) has received $25,000 from the
            Data Computing, Deep Learning,     Aerospace Corporation, in support of a project entitled “Wideband Array Antenna with Digital
            Computer Vision, Machine           Beamforming.”
            Learning, Artificial Intelligence,
            Robotics, and Biometrics.         •Xudong Jia (Engineering and Computer Science, Office of the Dean) has received $800,000
            Additionally, he is the Founder    from UCLA, in support of the project “Climate Action – Community-Driven Electric Vehicle
            and Co-Director of the Data        Charging Solution (CA-CLEAN),” and $25,126 from Cal Poly Pomona, in support of a project
            Science and Artificial Intelligence   entitled “Statewide Collision Data Analysis, Research Studies and Ranking Program.”
            Research Lab and the Founder of
            the Data Science and Artificial   •Christoph Schaal (Mechanical Engineering) has received $40,000 from the Aerospace
            Intelligence Research Group at     Corporation, in support of his project, “Concept Development and Feasibility Study for In-
            CSUN. Dr. Verma holds a B.S. in    Space Inspection of Bonded Joints.”
            Commerce from Delhi University,   •Maryam Tabibzadeh (Manufacturing Systems Engineering and Management) has received
            an M.S. in Computer Application    $51,660 from UCLA, in support of her project “Extending Human Reliability Analysis Methods
            from Bangalore University,         for Explicit Inclusion of Organizational Factors: Methodology and PRA Implications.”
            and both a Ph.D. and M.S. in
            Computer Science from the New
            Jersey Institute of Technology.



              FACULTY HONORED AT THE 2023

              ENGINEERS’ COUNCIL AWARDS BANQUET



            The 2023 Engineers’ Council awards banquet, an annual event   and sustained impact in
            that recognizes outstanding contributions by individuals in our   research, teaching, and
            community and throughout the world in the STEM (Science,   service and for providing
            Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) fields, was held   exceptional undergraduate
            on Feb. 25, 2023 at the Sheraton Universal Hotel honoring the   and graduate research
            achievements of many, including our faculty.         experiences for CSUN
                                                                 students; Shadi Mahjoob,
            The John J. Guarrera Engineering Educator of the Year award,   for outstanding contributions
            given to an individual who demonstrates professional qualities   to the field of computational,
            and has a top reputation for accomplishments and leadership,   experimental, and analytical heat transfer, and significant
            went to Dr. Nazaret Dermendjian, former chair of the Civil   accomplishments in instructional activities including
            Engineering and Construction Management Department,   leadership in senior design projects; Ricardo Medina, for
            for extraordinary commitment to students and outstanding   unwavering dedication to students and exemplary teaching;
            service to the Civil Engineering and Construction Management   Shahnam Mirzaei, in recognition of outstanding commitment
            Department and the College of Engineering and Computer   to developing a research culture among CSUN graduate
            Science at CSUN.                                     students in Computer Engineering; Ani Nahapetian, for
                                                                 excellence in engaging graduate and undergraduate students
            The Outstanding Engineering Achievement Merit Award   in research; Vidya Nandikolla, for outstanding contributions to
            recipients from our College are as follows: Xunfei Jiang, for   engineering education and research in the areas of autonomous
            excellence in teaching at multiple universities, outstanding   systems, biomedical robotics, and controls, employing many
            mentorship of undergraduate student research, and actively   undergraduate and graduate student researchers; Jack Ou,
            promoting diversity in the Computer Science discipline; Aram   in recognition of outstanding commitment and excellent
            Khachatourians, for outstanding contributions to engineering   performance in educating CSUN engineering students in the
            education through dedicated and innovative teaching and   areas of analog integrated circuits and RF electronic design;
            by supporting the students in the Mechanical Engineering   and, Shawn Sun, for exceptional research activities and
            department at CSUN; Bingbing Li, for outstanding achievement   continued contribution to the field of structural engineering.

                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     26]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[IN MEMORIAM

                                                                                Sadly, the College lost a few colleagues and
                                                                             friends  in the last couple of years.  We are thankful to
                                                                             have known them.  They will be sorely missed.


                                                                            STEPHEN GADOMSKI
                                                                                Professor Emeritus
                                                                            Stephen Gadomski ’69 ‘72
          CSUN STUDENTS GO                                                  Engineering, passed away
                                                                            January 22, 2022, he was 75.
          INTERSTELLAR AT JPL                                               Prof. Gadomski joined the CSUN
                                                                            faculty in 1978.  In 1998 he
                                                                            became Chair of the then Civil
                                                                            and Manufacturing Engineering
                                                                            Department (now Civil Engineering and Construction
          As an educational experience within the                           Management) until his retirement in 2010.
          college, students from California State
          University Northridge embarked on two                             PHILIP GILBERT
          separate trips to NASA's Jet Propulsion                               Dr. Philip Gilbert '74
          Laboratory (JPL) on January 9th and                               Engineering, professor emeritus
          January 16th 2024. Facilitated by the                             of Computer Science, passed
          college’s Leaders in Engineering and                              away on February 18, 2022. Dr.
          Computer Science club, the objective                              Gilbert joined the CECS faculty in
          was to provide students with a firsthand                          1974 and was one of the original
          experience of JPL's facilities and to deepen                      seven faculty members of the
          their understanding of the organization's background and history.  Computer Science Department
                                                                            when it started in 1975. During his tenure as faculty
          The journey began with an introduction to JPL at their on-campus museum,   he also served as Chair of the Computer Science
          offering insights into both historical achievements and future projects.
          Following this, students entered one of JPL’s clean rooms to witness the current   Department for some time.  He joined the Faculty Early
          preparations of the Europa Clipper for its space journey, with the rare opportunity   Retirement Program in Fall 1998.
          to see the spacecraft without its heat shielding. The experience of observing
          NASA employees in bunny suits at work provided a unique perspective on space   ICHIRO HASHIMOTO
          mission preparations.                                                 Dr. Ichiro Hashimoto, or
                                                                            Hash as many affectionately
          Afterwards, the group explored another facility, admiring replicas of previous   called him, a Professor Emeritus
          JPL projects, including one of the latest Mars rovers, Perserverence. Additionally,   of Electrical and Computer
          students gained a firsthand look at JPL's Mission Control, offering valuable insights   Engineering passed away March
          into the team's monitoring of incoming radar messaging. The visit overall helped   30, 2022 at the age of 85.  He
          enrich the students' understanding and appreciation for current and future   was regarded as a great mentor,
          advancements in space exploration technology.                     teacher and colleague. He had a
                                                                            passion for table tennis and worked as a coach for many
                                                                            years.  He retired in 2018.

                                                                            JACK SAMARA
                                                                                   Professor Jack Samara
                                                                            was a part time instructor
                                                                            for many years in the Civil
                                                                            Engineering and Construction
                                                                            Management Department. He
                                                                            passed away in November 2023.



                                                                            JAMES L. EASTON
                                                                                The College would also like to extend its heartfelt
                                                                            condolences to the family of James L. Easton, a
                                                                            longtime supporter of our College and the University,
                                                                            who passed away on Dec. 4, 2023.

        2024
                                                                                                                    27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[GIVING











                               SOLAR ENERGY PIONEER

                               BRIGHTENS LIVES AT CSUN





                                  Terry Jester, a longtime leader in     Thanks to the CSUN Foundation’s Matador Match
                               the field of solar energy, recently created   Challenge for 2022, which matched eligible donations
                               scholarships for students in the College of   dollar-for-dollar, Jester’s gift will support four students
                               Engineering and Computer Science at her   each year.
                               alma mater, California State University,
                               Northridge.                               To contribute to the Terry Jester Scholarship Fund or to
                                                                      create one of your own, please contact the CSUN Office of
                                  Jester ’79 (Mechanical Engineering)   Development at (818) 677-2786 or development@csun.edu.
                               was one of very few female mechanical   [CSUN Today article 9/13/23]
                               engineering students during her time
                              at CSUN. For more than 30 years, she
          has been an influential figure in the solar and other renewable
          energy industries, and in the electronic manufacturing industry —
          including executive positions and board memberships with numerous
          companies. Recently, she became managing director of North
          American operations for PI Berlin, a leading risk management and
          quality assurance service provider for solar equipment.



              “I’M INSPIRED BY OUR ABILITY AS
            ENGINEERS TO CHANGE THE WORLD,
           AND IF THIS SMALL PART CAN HELP A
          DESERVING ENGINEER, IT IS MY HONOR
          AND PRIVILEGE TO DO SO,” JESTER SAID.                     Dean Toutanji and Associate Dean Xudong Jia with recipients of the
                                                                    Terry Jester Scholarship, from left, Gurnoor Kaur, Vaishnavi Sen, Martha
            ” MY CSUN EDUCATION HAS SERVED                          Jauregui, and Zareen Supti.
              ME IN INFINITE WAYS, I’D LOVE TO
           HELP SOMEONE ELSE HAVE THE SAME
                STRONG WIND BEHIND THEM.”




              Jester has earned high praise for her work — including the 2015
          Women in Solar Energy Award from the American Solar Energy Society.

              The scholarships at CSUN will help two students each year
          develop their skills and talents to become the innovators of tomorrow.
          Preference will be given to students involved with the Society of
          Women Engineers and WISE (Women in Science and Engineering).

              “I’m inspired by our ability as engineers to change the world, and
          if this small part can help a deserving engineer, it is my honor and
          privilege to do so,” Jester said. ” My CSUN education has served me in
          infinite ways, I’d love to help someone else have the same strong wind
          behind them.”                                             Alumna Terry Jester '79 participating as Mechanical Engineering
                                                                    judge at the 2023 Senior Design Project Showcase

                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     28]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[ALUMNUS THANKS CECS

              WITH SCHOLARSHIP





                  Small things can have a major impact. Just ask Amol   and was looking for people with
               Gadgil, who left his native India for CSUN, where he earned   backgrounds in networking design
               his master’s degree in electrical engineering in 2009.   and electrical engineering. Although
               As a student specializing in optical networking, he was   he wasn’t hired there until 2012, he
               awarded a Dean’s Scholastic Excellence scholarship, which   credits the education he received at
               supplemented his student loan and helped him complete his   CSUN for giving him the skills that
               degree. He also took part in the Honors Co-op program.   opened the door to Google.

                                        “I studied under Professor   Today, as a technical program
                                    Bekir, who taught fiberoptics,”   manager at Google, Gadgil is part of a team that builds data
                                    he said. “She helped me get my   centers across the globe and connects them with a private optical
                                    first job through the Honor’s Co-  backbone. Because he is so grateful to the college, he recently
                                    op. I was at the right time and   decided to pay it forward by establishing the Amol Gadgil
                                    right place.”              Scholarship, for students majoring in any field within CECS. His
                                                               initial pledge of $5,000 over five years will be matched by Google,
                                        Gadgil’s Honors Co-op   making the full impact of his gift $10,000. The first scholarship
                                    placement, at a company called   was awarded in the 2023-24 academic year.
                                    MRV Communications, led to a
                                    full-time job as a senior optical   “Everything is expensive, but this is my small attempt to help
                                    engineer after he graduated.   anyone who needs it,” he explained.  “A small push can help get
                                    In 2010, Google reached out to   students over the line, so I’m really just doing my bit. If enough
                                    him because the company was   people start making even small contributions, it will have a bigger
                                    making major investments in   and bigger impact and help more and more students.”
                                    data centers and networking
     Amol Gadgil and family.



               ENDOWMENT HONORS

               STUDENT’S MEMORY


                  It was an especially heartbreaking case of being at   greatly eased his burden.
               the wrong place at the wrong time. On February 16, 2023,
               shortly after 12:30 am, Erick Barbosa-Guardado, a 19-year-  “I knew I couldn’t help Erick, but
               old civil engineering student at CSUN, was driving home   I thought perhaps I could help, in a
               from work when an armed robbery suspect being pursued by   small way, a financially struggling
               police ran a red light and crashed into Barbosa-Guardado’s   student with funds that could help
               car. Barbosa-Guardado, remembered by his aunt as “a really   them better succeed at CSUN, in a
               good guy” and excellent student, was killed in the collision,   similar manner that Dr. Ray Landis
               a promising life tragically cut short.          reached out for help for me,” he
                                                               said. “This endowment is my way
                  The story resonated deeply with a CECS alumnus who   of recognizing a loss to the future
               thought back to his time in the college and was moved   of engineering due to Erick’s tragic
               to make a gift establishing an endowment in Barbosa-  death, which prevented him from
               Guardado’s memory to help engineering or computer   making what I assert would have
               science students with financial need. The alumnus, who   been a positive influence on society.”
               prefers to remain anonymous, remembered his own
               financial struggles while studying engineering at CSUN   Pictured, the first recipient of the Erick
               in the early 1970s and how a part-time job tutoring MEP   Barbosa-Guardado Memorial Scholarship,
        2024   students and a scholarship from the Alumni Association   Pratheeksha Rajashekar, at the 2023
                                                               Donor Scholar Reception.                             29]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[CSUN's Timber-Strong

              Design Build project
              at PSWS














































































                                                                                                             SPECTRA
     30]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[2024
                                                                                                                    31]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[NON-PROFIT ORG.
                                                                                                         U.S. POSTAGE
                                                                                                           PAID
                                                                                                           CSUN
      College of Engineering and Computer Science
      18111 Nordhoff Street
      Northridge, CA 91330-8295





      GIVING TO THE
      COLLEGE


      Your gift makes a difference in the lives of our
      students. To support the College of Engineering
      and Computer Science, you can make a gift by
      check or online. Please make checks payable to
      CSUN Foundation and specify your gift
      designation in the memo line or include an
      accompanying note.  Mail checks to:
         The CSUN Foundation
         Valera Hall 110
         California State University, Northridge
         18111 Nordhoff Street
         Northridge, CA 91330-8296

                 To make a gift online visit
                 https://engage.csun.edu/givenow
                 or scan the QR code.
        SCAN TO
      GIVE ONLINE









































                                                                                                 2023 Commencement Ceremony.
                                                                                                 Photo by Lee Choo]]></page></pages></Search>